14.4, honesty.
You'll find this in Chapter 5 of the Code
of Ethics and Professional Conduct.
Honesty.
Description of honesty.
Honesty is our duty to
understand the truth and to act in a
truthful manner both in our
communications and in our conduct.
Honesty, aspirational standards.
As practitioners in the
global project management
community, one, we earnestly
seek to understand the truth.
Two, we are truthful.
in our communications and in our conduct.
3.
We provide accurate information in a
timely manner.
Comment.
An implication of these provisions is that
we take appropriate steps to ensure that
the information we are
based on our decisions upon or
providing to others is
accurate, reliable and timely.
This includes having the courage to share
bad use even when it
may be poorly received.
Also, when outcomes are negative, we avoid
burying information or
shifting blame to others.
When outcomes are positive, we avoid taking
credit for the achievement of others.
These provisions reinforce our commitment
to be both honest and responsible.
Four, we make commitments and promises
implied or explicit in good faith.
We strive to create an environment in
which others feel safe to tell the truth.
Honesty, mandatory standards.
As practitioners of the global project
management community, we require the
following of ourselves and our fellow
practitioners.
One, we do not engage in or condone
behaviour that is designed to deceive
others, including but not limited to
making misleading or false statements,
stating have truths, providing information
out of context, or withholding information
that, if known, would render our
statements as misleading or incomplete.
Two, we do not engage in
dishonest behavior with the
intention of personal gain
or at the expense of another.
Now actually I have an issue with standard
number two.
It says we do not engage in dishonest
behavior with the intention of personal
gain or the expensive another because this
sounds like well it's okay to be dishonest
as long as you don't intend to gain personally
or at the expense of another person.
I think it should just be we do not engage
in dishonest behavior.
And that's actually reminded me of
something.
In the earlier days of the PMP
examination, they used to have questions
on the exam on the Code of Ethics and
Professional Conduct.
The original Code of
Ethics and Professional
Conduct was actually
like a little one-sheet thing.
That's quite a few sheets that's been
expanded.
out, but you don't actually
get specific questions
on the Code of Ethics
and Professional Conduct.
What you do get questions where you need
to understand the code in order to answer
the question because you might get two
answers which appear correct.
One of them is obeying Code
of Ethics and Professional
Conduct and the other
one is not obeying the code.
And so obviously you choose the answer
which obeys the Code.
Comment, the aspirational standards exhort
us to be truthful, half-truths and
non-disclosures intended
to mislead stakeholders or as
unprofessional is affirmately
making misrepresentations.
We develop credibility by providing
complete and accurate information.
And that brings us to the end of honesty.
We have reached the end of the course.
Thank you for joining me on this journey
and I'm sure that you're not got a much
better understanding of the PIMBOC guide
and the Code of Ethics and Professional
Conduct and probably, you know, a little
bit more about project management itself.
And with that understanding, it will
become clearer as you watch the videos
again and you progressively elaborate your
knowledge.
Thank you.
And good luck with the PMP examination.